Applied and Decorative Arts Medium Format Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Applied and Decorative Arts Medium Format Photograph Collection
1900-2005
VRC 9
Yale University Arts Library
17.4
11 boxes
Collection of medium format mounted black and white and color reproductions of Western applied and decorative arts, predominantly European. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Conditions Governing Access
These materials are stored offsite at the Library Shelving Facility. For access to the materials, please make a request at the Art & Architecture Library.
Arrangement
Arrange alphabetically by object type. Further divisions vary either by country or region, by chronological order, stylistic designation, or by individual artist name.
Scope and Contents
Collection of medium format mounted black and white and color reproductions of Western applied and decorative arts, predominantly European. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Decorative arts; Photographs; Reproductions
- Inventory.
  - Armor and Weapons., 13 (Box 1)
    - Spain., 13 (Box 1)
  - Ceramics., 2 (Box 1)
    - Aegean., 1 (Box 1)
    - Persian., 1 (Box 1)
  - Furniture., 5 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous., 1 (Box 1)
    - Gothic., 1 (Box 1)
    - English., 1 (Box 1)
      - Adam, Robert, active 1775., 1 (Box 1)
    - French., 2 (Box 1)
      - Louis XVI., 2 (Box 1)
  - Gems., 2 (Box 1)
    - Aegean., 1 (Box 1)
    - Roman., 1 (Box 1)
  - Ivory., 2 (Box 1)
    - Byzantine., 2 (Box 1)
  - Manuscripts., 55
    - Hindu., 1 (Box 2)
    - Islamic., 10 (Box 2)
    - Early Christian., 6 (Box 2)
    - Romanesque., 1 (Box 2)
    - Byzantine., 1 (Box 2)
    - Carolingian., 3 (Box 2)
    - Austria., 1 (Box 2)
    - Britain., 1 (Box 2)
    - Ethiopia., 1 (Box 2)
    - Flanders., 2 (Box 2)
    - France., 8 (Box 2)
    - Germany., 4 (Box 3)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes Gutenberg Bible.
    - Holland., 1 (Box 3)
    - Italy., 12 (Box 3)
    - Spain., 3 (Box 3)
  - Maps., 15 (Box 4)
  - Metal., 15 (Box 4)
    Includes Silver.
  - Mosaics., 26 (Box 5)
    - Roman., 4 (Box 5)
    - Jewish, VIII C., 1 (Box 5)
    - Byzantine., 20 (Box 5)
    - Early Medieval., 1 (Box 5)
  - Photography., 10 (Box 5)
    Includes a folder of Ansel Adam reproductions.
    - Miscellaneous works., 2 (Box 5)
    - Known artists., 8 (Box 5)
      - Adams, Ansel, 1902-1984., 3 (Box 5)
      - Callahan, Harry, 1912-1999., 1 (Box 5)
      - Haltoric, T., 1 (Box 5)
      - Mabee, Zell., 1 (Box 5)
      - Niepce, Nicephore, 1765-1833., 1 (Box 5)
      - Ylla, ?., 1 (Box 5)
  - Prints., 88 (Box 5)
    Includes a folder of miscellaneous prints.
    - Unknown artists., 2 (Box 6)
    - Known artists., 86 (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous artists, A-Z., 28 (Box 6)
        - Altdorfer, Albrecht, 1480-1538., 1 (Box 6)
        - Baldung, Hans, 1484-1545., 1 (Box 6)
        - Barbari, Jacopo de, 1449/50-1515., 1 (Box 6)
        - Benton, Thomas Hart, 1889-1975., 2 (Box 6)
        - Burgkmair, Hans, 1473-1531., 2 (Box 6)
        - Cassatt, Mary, 1855-1926., 1 (Box 6)
        - Choki, Eishosai, 1785-1805., 1 (Box 6)
        - Cranach, Lucas, 1472-1553., 1 (Box 6)
        - Dore, Paul Gustave, 1832-1883., 2 (Box 6)
        - Elliot, D. G., active 1860-1877., 1 (Box 6)
        - Klee, Paul, 1879-1940., 1 (Box 6)
        - Mategna, Andrea, 1431-1506., 1 (Box 6)
        - Marini, Marino, 1901-1980., 2 (Box 6)
        - Miro, Joan, 1893-1983., 1 (Box 6)
        - Picasso, Pablo, 1881-1973., 1 (Box 6)
        - Raimondi, Marcantonio, 1480-1527., 1 (Box 6)
        - St. Aubin, Augustin de, 1736-1807., 1 (Box 6)
        - Tiepolo, Giovanni Battista, 1696-1770., 1 (Box 6)
        - Tranchant, Maurice, XX C., 1 (Box 6)
        - Vesalius, Andreas, XVI C., 2 (Box 6)
        - Visscher, Nicholas, 1580-1660., 1 (Box 6)
      - Individual artists, A-Z., 58 (Box 7)
        - Bonnard, Pierre, 1867-1947., 6 (Box 7)
        - Bosse, Abraham, 1602-1676., 4 (Box 7)
        - Currier and Ives., 10 (Box 7)
        - Durer, Albrecht, 1471-1528., 15 (Box 8)
        - Piranesi, Giovanni Battista, 1720-1778., 3 (Box 8)
        - Rembrandt van Rijn, 1606-1669., 5 (Box 8)
        - Toulouse-Lautrec, Henri de, 1874-1899., 14 (Box 9)
        - Van Leyden, Lucas, 1494-1523., 1 (Box 9)
  - Rugs., 6 (Box 9)
  - Stained Glass., 18 (Box 10)
    Includes a folder of miscellaneous photographs.
    - Britain., 1 (Box 10)
    - France., 15 (Box 10)
    - Italy., 2 (Box 10)
  - Tapestry., 17 (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous works., 2 (Box 11)
    - Coptic., 1 (Box 11)
    - Belgium., 1 (Box 11)
    - Flanders., 7 (Box 11)
    - France., 5 (Box 11)
    - Germany., 1 (Box 11)
  - Textiles., 4 (Box 11)
    - VI to VII Century., 4 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous/Gumbo Mud., 7 (Box 11)